{"problemsArray": [
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 4/(x + 7) \u003d (2x + 5)/(x + 1)(x + 7)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 7)\n(x + 7) + 4(x + 1) \u003d (2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 7) + 4(x + 1) - (2x + 5) \u003d 0\n3(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 9) + 1/2(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 9)(x + 1)", "answer": "5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(x + 1)\n2(x + 1) + (x + 9)/2 \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 1) + (x + 9)/2 - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n(-x + 5)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(2x + 9) + 2/(4x + 9) \u003d 1/(2x + 9)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 9)\n3(4x + 9) + 2(2x + 9) \u003d (4x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(4x + 9) + 2(2x + 9) - (4x + 9) \u003d 0\n12(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 4) + 1/(x + 8) \u003d (4x + 3)/(x + 4)(x + 8)", "answer": "17", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 8)\n2(x + 8) + (x + 4) \u003d (4x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 8) + (x + 4) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\n(-x + 17) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n17\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 5) + 2/(x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 1)/(x + 5)(x + 10)", "answer": "-27", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 10)\n2(x + 10) + 2(x + 5) \u003d 3(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 10) + 2(x + 5) - 3(x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x + 27) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-27\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 2) + 3/(x + 8) \u003d (2x + 1)/(x + 2)(x + 8)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 8)\n2(x + 8) + 3(x + 2) \u003d (2x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 8) + 3(x + 2) - (2x + 1) \u003d 0\n3(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(x + 3) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 8)/(x + 3)(x + 1)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1)/2 + (x + 3) \u003d (3x + 8)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1)/2 + (x + 3) - (3x + 8) \u003d 0\n(-x - 7)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(4x + 5) + 4/3(x + 2) \u003d (4x + 11)/(4x + 5)(x + 2)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 5)(x + 2)\n(x + 2) + 4(4x + 5)/3 \u003d (4x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 2) + 4(4x + 5)/3 - (4x + 11) \u003d 0\n7(x - 1)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(x + 5) + 1/(x + 9) \u003d (2x + 7)/(x + 5)(x + 9)", "answer": "-23", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 9)\n3(x + 9)/2 + (x + 5) \u003d (2x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 9)/2 + (x + 5) - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\n(x + 23)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-23\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 2/(x + 8) \u003d (x + 4)/(x + 1)(x + 8)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 8)\n(x + 8) + 2(x + 1) \u003d (x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 8) + 2(x + 1) - (x + 4) \u003d 0\n2(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(4x + 1) + 1/(3x + 2) \u003d (2x + 7)/(4x + 1)(3x + 2)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 1)(3x + 2)\n3(3x + 2) + (4x + 1) \u003d (2x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(3x + 2) + (4x + 1) - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\n11(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 5) + 1/2(2x + 1) \u003d (2x + 3)/(x + 5)(2x + 1)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(2x + 1)\n(2x + 1) + (x + 5)/2 \u003d (2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 1) + (x + 5)/2 - (2x + 3) \u003d 0\n(x + 1)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 1) + 1/(x + 7) \u003d 1/(x + 1)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)\n3(x + 7) + (x + 1) \u003d (x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 7) + (x + 1) - (x + 7) \u003d 0\n3(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(2x + 9) + 3/(2x + 7) \u003d 3(x + 3)/(2x + 9)(2x + 7)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 9)(2x + 7)\n(2x + 7) + 3(2x + 9) \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 7) + 3(2x + 9) - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\n5(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(4x + 11) + 3/(3x + 10) \u003d (3x + 8)/(4x + 11)(3x + 10)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 11)(3x + 10)\n2(3x + 10) + 3(4x + 11) \u003d (3x + 8)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(3x + 10) + 3(4x + 11) - (3x + 8) \u003d 0\n15(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 11) + 2/(2x + 3) \u003d (x + 8)/(x + 11)(2x + 3)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(2x + 3)\n2(2x + 3) + 2(x + 11) \u003d (x + 8)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(2x + 3) + 2(x + 11) - (x + 8) \u003d 0\n5(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/3(x + 1) + 3/(x + 9) \u003d 2(x + 2)/(x + 1)(x + 9)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 9)\n2(x + 9)/3 + 3(x + 1) \u003d 2(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 9)/3 + 3(x + 1) - 2(x + 2) \u003d 0\n5(x + 3)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 4/(x + 9) \u003d (3x + 7)/(x + 2)(x + 9)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 9)\n(x + 9) + 4(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 9) + 4(x + 2) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n2(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(2x + 9) + 1/(x + 3) \u003d 2(x + 2)/(2x + 9)(x + 3)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 9)(x + 3)\n(x + 3) + (2x + 9) \u003d 2(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 3) + (2x + 9) - 2(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 8) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(x + 8) + 2/(x + 5) \u003d 3(x + 1)/(x + 8)(x + 5)", "answer": "-11", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 8)(x + 5)\n4(x + 5) + 2(x + 8) \u003d 3(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 5) + 2(x + 8) - 3(x + 1) \u003d 0\n3(x + 11) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-11\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(2x + 5) + 1/(3x + 2) \u003d (3x + 5)/(2x + 5)(3x + 2)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(3x + 2)\n(3x + 2)/2 + (2x + 5) \u003d (3x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 2)/2 + (2x + 5) - (3x + 5) \u003d 0\n(x + 2)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(x + 4) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 10)/(x + 4)(x + 1)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 1)\n4(x + 1) + (x + 4) \u003d (3x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 1) + (x + 4) - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\n2(x - 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 5) + 3/(x + 5) \u003d (x + 11)/(2x + 5)(x + 5)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(x + 5)\n2(x + 5) + 3(2x + 5) \u003d (x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 5) + 3(2x + 5) - (x + 11) \u003d 0\n7(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 4/(x + 7) \u003d (4x + 3)/(x + 1)(x + 7)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 7)\n(x + 7) + 4(x + 1) \u003d (4x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 7) + 4(x + 1) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\n(x + 8) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 7) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 5)/(3x + 7)(x + 1)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 7)(x + 1)\n2(x + 1) + (3x + 7) \u003d (3x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 1) + (3x + 7) - (3x + 5) \u003d 0\n2(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 7) + 1/2(x + 5) \u003d (x + 11)/(x + 7)(x + 5)", "answer": "5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 7)(x + 5)\n(x + 5) + (x + 7)/2 \u003d (x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 5) + (x + 7)/2 - (x + 11) \u003d 0\n(x - 5)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 2) + 1/(x + 10) \u003d (4x + 9)/(x + 2)(x + 10)", "answer": "13", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 10)\n2(x + 10) + (x + 2) \u003d (4x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 10) + (x + 2) - (4x + 9) \u003d 0\n(-x + 13) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n13\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 3) + 1/(3x + 7) \u003d (x + 11)/(x + 3)(3x + 7)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(3x + 7)\n(3x + 7)/2 + (x + 3) \u003d (x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 7)/2 + (x + 3) - (x + 11) \u003d 0\n3(x - 3)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 6) + 2/(2x + 11) \u003d (2x + 1)/(x + 6)(2x + 11)", "answer": "-11", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 6)(2x + 11)\n(2x + 11) + 2(x + 6) \u003d (2x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 11) + 2(x + 6) - (2x + 1) \u003d 0\n2(x + 11) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-11\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(x + 10) + 4/(x + 4) \u003d 4(x + 2)/(x + 10)(x + 4)", "answer": "-12", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 4)\n4(x + 4) + 4(x + 10) \u003d 4(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 4) + 4(x + 10) - 4(x + 2) \u003d 0\n4(x + 12) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-12\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 4/(2x + 9) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 1)(2x + 9)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(2x + 9)\n(2x + 9) + 4(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 9) + 4(x + 1) - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n3(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(x + 5) + 1/(2x + 5) \u003d (3x + 1)/(x + 5)(2x + 5)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(2x + 5)\n4(2x + 5) + (x + 5) \u003d (3x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(2x + 5) + (x + 5) - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\n6(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 11) + 1/(x + 8) \u003d 3(x + 1)/(2x + 11)(x + 8)", "answer": "-24", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 11)(x + 8)\n2(x + 8) + (2x + 11) \u003d 3(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 8) + (2x + 11) - 3(x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x + 24) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-24\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 1/(2x + 5) \u003d 4/(2x + 5)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)\n(2x + 5) + (x + 2) \u003d 4(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 5) + (x + 2) - 4(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(-x - 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 1/(2x + 9) \u003d (x + 10)/(x + 1)(2x + 9)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(2x + 9)\n(2x + 9) + (x + 1) \u003d (x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 9) + (x + 1) - (x + 10) \u003d 0\n2(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(4x + 3) + 1/(2x + 7) \u003d (x + 10)/(4x + 3)(2x + 7)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 3)(2x + 7)\n(2x + 7) + (4x + 3) \u003d (x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 7) + (4x + 3) - (x + 10) \u003d 0\n5(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/3(x + 3) + 3/(x + 6) \u003d (3x + 1)/(x + 3)(x + 6)", "answer": "-30", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 6)\n(x + 6)/3 + 3(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 6)/3 + 3(x + 3) - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x + 30)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-30\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 11) + 1/(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 2)/(2x + 11)(x + 3)", "answer": "-15", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 11)(x + 3)\n2(x + 3) + (2x + 11) \u003d (3x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 3) + (2x + 11) - (3x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 15) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-15\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 1/(3x + 11) \u003d 3(x + 1)/(x + 2)(3x + 11)", "answer": "-10", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(3x + 11)\n(3x + 11) + (x + 2) \u003d 3(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 11) + (x + 2) - 3(x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x + 10) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-10\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 9) + 1/(x + 5) \u003d (3x + 10)/(2x + 9)(x + 5)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 9)(x + 5)\n2(x + 5) + (2x + 9) \u003d (3x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 5) + (2x + 9) - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\n(x + 9) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 2) + 1/3(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 1)/(x + 2)(x + 2)", "answer": "-17", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 2)\n3(x + 2) + (x + 2)/3 \u003d (3x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 2) + (x + 2)/3 - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x + 17)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-17\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 2/(4x + 3) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 2)(4x + 3)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(4x + 3)\n(4x + 3) + 2(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(4x + 3) + 2(x + 2) - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n3(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(3x + 11) + 1/2(x + 5) \u003d (3x + 7)/(3x + 11)(x + 5)", "answer": "7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 11)(x + 5)\n(x + 5) + (3x + 11)/2 \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 5) + (3x + 11)/2 - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n(-x + 7)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 11) + 2/(x + 5) \u003d 2(x + 2)/(x + 11)(x + 5)", "answer": "-23", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(x + 5)\n(x + 5) + 2(x + 11) \u003d 2(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 5) + 2(x + 11) - 2(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 23) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-23\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 9) + 3/(x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 3)/(x + 9)(x + 10)", "answer": "-28", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(x + 10)\n(x + 10) + 3(x + 9) \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 10) + 3(x + 9) - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\n(x + 28) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-28\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 2/(3x + 10) \u003d (2x + 11)/(x + 2)(3x + 10)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(3x + 10)\n(3x + 10) + 2(x + 2) \u003d (2x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 10) + 2(x + 2) - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\n3(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 10) + 1/2(x + 3) \u003d (x + 2)/(x + 10)(x + 3)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 3)\n2(x + 3) + (x + 10)/2 \u003d (x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 3) + (x + 10)/2 - (x + 2) \u003d 0\n3(x + 6)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(2x + 7) + 4/(2x + 9) \u003d 2(x + 4)/(2x + 7)(2x + 9)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 7)(2x + 9)\n4(2x + 9) + 4(2x + 7) \u003d 2(x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(2x + 9) + 4(2x + 7) - 2(x + 4) \u003d 0\n14(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(4x + 5) + 1/(x + 6) \u003d (4x + 3)/(4x + 5)(x + 6)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 5)(x + 6)\n2(x + 6) + (4x + 5) \u003d (4x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 6) + (4x + 5) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\n2(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/3(x + 1) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d 2(x + 5)/(x + 1)(x + 1)", "answer": "23", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 1)\n4(x + 1)/3 + (x + 1) \u003d 2(x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 1)/3 + (x + 1) - 2(x + 5) \u003d 0\n(x - 23)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n23\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(x + 10) + 3/(x + 11) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(x + 10)(x + 11)", "answer": "-17", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 11)\n4(x + 11) + 3(x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 11) + 3(x + 10) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n4(x + 17) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-17\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 1/2(2x + 5) \u003d (2x + 7)/(x + 2)(2x + 5)", "answer": "2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(2x + 5)\n(2x + 5) + (x + 2)/2 \u003d (2x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 5) + (x + 2)/2 - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\n(x - 2)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(3x + 1) + 2/(3x + 11) \u003d (3x + 7)/(3x + 1)(3x + 11)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 1)(3x + 11)\n(3x + 11) + 2(3x + 1) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 11) + 2(3x + 1) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n6(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 2) + 1/(x + 6) \u003d (3x + 8)/(3x + 2)(x + 6)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 2)(x + 6)\n2(x + 6) + (3x + 2) \u003d (3x + 8)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 6) + (3x + 2) - (3x + 8) \u003d 0\n2(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(2x + 1) + 1/2(2x + 5) \u003d (3x + 11)/(2x + 1)(2x + 5)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(2x + 5)\n3(2x + 5)/2 + (2x + 1)/2 \u003d (3x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(2x + 5)/2 + (2x + 1)/2 - (3x + 11) \u003d 0\n(x - 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 9) + 1/(x + 4) \u003d (x + 6)/(x + 9)(x + 4)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(x + 4)\n(x + 4) + (x + 9) \u003d (x + 6)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 4) + (x + 9) - (x + 6) \u003d 0\n(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 11) + 1/(x + 5) \u003d 3(x + 3)/(x + 11)(x + 5)", "answer": "-17", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(x + 5)\n3(x + 5) + (x + 11) \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 5) + (x + 11) - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\n(x + 17) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-17\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 7) + 2/(x + 2) \u003d 4/(2x + 7)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 7)\n2(x + 2) + 2(2x + 7) \u003d 4(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 2) + 2(2x + 7) - 4(x + 2) \u003d 0\n2(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 10) + 3/4(x + 1) \u003d (2x + 7)/(x + 10)(x + 1)", "answer": "6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 1)\n(x + 1) + 3(x + 10)/4 \u003d (2x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 1) + 3(x + 10)/4 - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\n(-x + 6)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 1) + 1/(x + 4) \u003d 3(x + 3)/(2x + 1)(x + 4)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(x + 4)\n2(x + 4) + (2x + 1) \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 4) + (2x + 1) - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\nx \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(3x + 2) + 1/2(x + 3) \u003d (x + 10)/(3x + 2)(x + 3)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 2)(x + 3)\n3(x + 3) + (3x + 2)/2 \u003d (x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 3) + (3x + 2)/2 - (x + 10) \u003d 0\n7(x)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 1) + 1/(x + 7) \u003d (2x + 11)/(2x + 1)(x + 7)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(x + 7)\n2(x + 7) + (2x + 1) \u003d (2x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 7) + (2x + 1) - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\n2(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 2) + 2/3(x + 1) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(x + 2)(x + 1)", "answer": "-17", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1) + 2(x + 2)/3 \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1) + 2(x + 2)/3 - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n(-x - 17)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-17\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/3(x + 3) + 1/2(x + 2) \u003d 1/(x + 3)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)\n2(x + 2)/3 + (x + 3)/2 \u003d (x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 2)/3 + (x + 3)/2 - (x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 5)/6 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(2x + 1) + 1/(x + 5) \u003d (2x + 9)/(2x + 1)(x + 5)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(x + 5)\n4(x + 5) + (2x + 1) \u003d (2x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 5) + (2x + 1) - (2x + 9) \u003d 0\n4(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 8) + 1/(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 11)/(x + 8)(x + 3)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 8)(x + 3)\n3(x + 3) + (x + 8) \u003d (3x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 3) + (x + 8) - (3x + 11) \u003d 0\n(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 9) + 1/(3x + 5) \u003d (x + 1)/(x + 9)(3x + 5)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(3x + 5)\n2(3x + 5) + (x + 9) \u003d (x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(3x + 5) + (x + 9) - (x + 1) \u003d 0\n6(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 5) + 3/2(2x + 5) \u003d 2/(x + 5)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)\n(2x + 5)/2 + 3(x + 5)/2 \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 5)/2 + 3(x + 5)/2 - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n-3(x)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 5) + 4/(x + 2) \u003d 2(x + 4)/(x + 5)(x + 2)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 2)\n2(x + 2) + 4(x + 5) \u003d 2(x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 2) + 4(x + 5) - 2(x + 4) \u003d 0\n4(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(3x + 4) + 1/4(x + 1) \u003d 2(2x + 1)/(3x + 4)(x + 1)", "answer": "8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 4)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1) + (3x + 4)/4 \u003d 2(2x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1) + (3x + 4)/4 - 2(2x + 1) \u003d 0\n(-x + 8)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(2x + 1) + 2/3(x + 1) \u003d (2x + 9)/(2x + 1)(x + 1)", "answer": "22", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(x + 1)\n(x + 1) + 2(2x + 1)/3 \u003d (2x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 1) + 2(2x + 1)/3 - (2x + 9) \u003d 0\n(x - 22)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n22\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 3/(4x + 3) \u003d 2(2x + 3)/(x + 2)(4x + 3)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(4x + 3)\n(4x + 3) + 3(x + 2) \u003d 2(2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(4x + 3) + 3(x + 2) - 2(2x + 3) \u003d 0\n3(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 3) + 1/2(2x + 3) \u003d (4x + 11)/(x + 3)(2x + 3)", "answer": "7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(2x + 3)\n2(2x + 3) + (x + 3)/2 \u003d (4x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(2x + 3) + (x + 3)/2 - (4x + 11) \u003d 0\n(x - 7)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 1) + 2/(x + 4) \u003d 2(2x + 1)/(3x + 1)(x + 4)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 1)(x + 4)\n2(x + 4) + 2(3x + 1) \u003d 2(2x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 4) + 2(3x + 1) - 2(2x + 1) \u003d 0\n4(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 11) + 1/(2x + 7) \u003d (4x + 5)/(x + 11)(2x + 7)", "answer": "13", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(2x + 7)\n(2x + 7) + (x + 11) \u003d (4x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 7) + (x + 11) - (4x + 5) \u003d 0\n(-x + 13) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n13\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(2x + 5) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 4)/(2x + 5)(x + 1)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(x + 1)\n(x + 1)/2 + (2x + 5) \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 1)/2 + (2x + 5) - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n(-x + 3)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 1/(2x + 9) \u003d (x + 2)/(x + 1)(2x + 9)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(2x + 9)\n(2x + 9) + (x + 1) \u003d (x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 9) + (x + 1) - (x + 2) \u003d 0\n2(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(3x + 4) + 1/4(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 10)/(3x + 4)(x + 1)", "answer": "8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 4)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1) + (3x + 4)/4 \u003d (3x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1) + (3x + 4)/4 - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\n3(x - 8)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 4) + 2/(3x + 1) \u003d (4x + 7)/(x + 4)(3x + 1)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(3x + 1)\n(3x + 1) + 2(x + 4) \u003d (4x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 1) + 2(x + 4) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\n(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(3x + 5) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d 4/(3x + 5)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 5)\n3(x + 1) + (3x + 5) \u003d 4(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1) + (3x + 5) - 4(x + 1) \u003d 0\n2(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(3x + 5) + 2/(3x + 4) \u003d 4(x + 1)/(3x + 5)(3x + 4)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 5)(3x + 4)\n(3x + 4) + 2(3x + 5) \u003d 4(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 4) + 2(3x + 5) - 4(x + 1) \u003d 0\n5(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 4) + 4/(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 10)/(x + 4)(x + 3)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 3)\n(x + 3)/2 + 4(x + 4) \u003d (3x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 3)/2 + 4(x + 4) - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\n3(x + 5)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 3) + 2/(4x + 3) \u003d (4x + 7)/(x + 3)(4x + 3)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(4x + 3)\n(4x + 3) + 2(x + 3) \u003d (4x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(4x + 3) + 2(x + 3) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\n2(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 1/(3x + 10) \u003d 3/(3x + 10)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 10)\n(3x + 10) + (x + 1) \u003d 3(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 10) + (x + 1) - 3(x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x + 8) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 10) + 2/(x + 3) \u003d 2(x + 4)/(x + 10)(x + 3)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 3)\n2(x + 3) + 2(x + 10) \u003d 2(x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 3) + 2(x + 10) - 2(x + 4) \u003d 0\n2(x + 9) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(x + 5) + 3/4(x + 2) \u003d 3(x + 1)/(x + 5)(x + 2)", "answer": "5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 2)\n3(x + 2)/2 + 3(x + 5)/4 \u003d 3(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 2)/2 + 3(x + 5)/4 - 3(x + 1) \u003d 0\n-3(x - 5)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 5) + 4/(4x + 1) \u003d (x + 7)/(x + 5)(4x + 1)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(4x + 1)\n(4x + 1) + 4(x + 5) \u003d (x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(4x + 1) + 4(x + 5) - (x + 7) \u003d 0\n7(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 10) + 1/(x + 9) \u003d 2(x + 5)/(3x + 10)(x + 9)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 10)(x + 9)\n2(x + 9) + (3x + 10) \u003d 2(x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 9) + (3x + 10) - 2(x + 5) \u003d 0\n3(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 1) + 1/(2x + 9) \u003d (4x + 3)/(2x + 1)(2x + 9)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(2x + 9)\n2(2x + 9) + (2x + 1) \u003d (4x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(2x + 9) + (2x + 1) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\n2(x + 8) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 8) + 3/(x + 9) \u003d (x + 2)/(3x + 8)(x + 9)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 8)(x + 9)\n2(x + 9) + 3(3x + 8) \u003d (x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 9) + 3(3x + 8) - (x + 2) \u003d 0\n10(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(4x + 7) + 1/(2x + 7) \u003d 4(x + 1)/(4x + 7)(2x + 7)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 7)(2x + 7)\n3(2x + 7) + (4x + 7) \u003d 4(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(2x + 7) + (4x + 7) - 4(x + 1) \u003d 0\n6(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 4) + 1/2(2x + 5) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(x + 4)(2x + 5)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(2x + 5)\n(2x + 5)/2 + (x + 4)/2 \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 5)/2 + (x + 4)/2 - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n-3(x + 1)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 8) + 1/(x + 8) \u003d (2x + 9)/(x + 8)(x + 8)", "answer": "-15", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 8)(x + 8)\n2(x + 8) + (x + 8) \u003d (2x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 8) + (x + 8) - (2x + 9) \u003d 0\n(x + 15) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-15\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/3(x + 1) + 1/(2x + 11) \u003d (4x + 9)/(x + 1)(2x + 11)", "answer": "20", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(2x + 11)\n4(2x + 11)/3 + (x + 1) \u003d (4x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(2x + 11)/3 + (x + 1) - (4x + 9) \u003d 0\n(-x + 20)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n20\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(2x + 7) + 2/3(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 11)/(2x + 7)(x + 1)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 7)(x + 1)\n4(x + 1) + 2(2x + 7)/3 \u003d (3x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 1) + 2(2x + 7)/3 - (3x + 11) \u003d 0\n7(x - 1)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/4(x + 2) + 3/(3x + 4) \u003d (4x + 9)/(x + 2)(3x + 4)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(3x + 4)\n3(3x + 4)/4 + 3(x + 2) \u003d (4x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(3x + 4)/4 + 3(x + 2) - (4x + 9) \u003d 0\n5(x)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 6) + 4/(3x + 10) \u003d 4(x + 1)/(x + 6)(3x + 10)", "answer": "-10", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 6)(3x + 10)\n(3x + 10) + 4(x + 6) \u003d 4(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 10) + 4(x + 6) - 4(x + 1) \u003d 0\n3(x + 10) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-10\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/3(x + 2) + 2/(2x + 3) \u003d 3/(2x + 3)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)\n2(2x + 3)/3 + 2(x + 2) \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(2x + 3)/3 + 2(x + 2) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(x + 3) + 1/3(x + 1) \u003d (2x + 7)/(x + 3)(x + 1)", "answer": "-27", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1)/2 + (x + 3)/3 \u003d (2x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1)/2 + (x + 3)/3 - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\n(-x - 27)/6 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-27\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(2x + 3) + 3/2(2x + 3) \u003d (4x + 1)/(2x + 3)(2x + 3)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(2x + 3)\n3(2x + 3)/2 + 3(2x + 3)/2 \u003d (4x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(2x + 3)/2 + 3(2x + 3)/2 - (4x + 1) \u003d 0\n2(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 11) + 1/(x + 3) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(3x + 11)(x + 3)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 11)(x + 3)\n2(x + 3) + (3x + 11) \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 3) + (3x + 11) - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 1) + 3/(x + 6) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 1)(x + 6)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 6)\n(x + 6)/2 + 3(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 6)/2 + 3(x + 1) - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n(x + 4)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(2x + 9) + 2/(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 8)/(2x + 9)(x + 2)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 9)(x + 2)\n3(x + 2) + 2(2x + 9) \u003d (3x + 8)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 2) + 2(2x + 9) - (3x + 8) \u003d 0\n4(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(3x + 8) + 3/(x + 3) \u003d (4x + 3)/(3x + 8)(x + 3)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 8)(x + 3)\n(x + 3) + 3(3x + 8) \u003d (4x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 3) + 3(3x + 8) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\n6(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(2x + 5) + 2/(x + 1) \u003d (4x + 7)/(2x + 5)(x + 1)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1) + 2(2x + 5) \u003d (4x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1) + 2(2x + 5) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\n3(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(3x + 2) + 2/(x + 11) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(3x + 2)(x + 11)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 2)(x + 11)\n4(x + 11) + 2(3x + 2) \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 11) + 2(3x + 2) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n7(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 3) + 2/(x + 8) \u003d 4(x + 2)/(2x + 3)(x + 8)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(x + 8)\n2(x + 8) + 2(2x + 3) \u003d 4(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 8) + 2(2x + 3) - 4(x + 2) \u003d 0\n2(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 11) + 2/(x + 7) \u003d 2(x + 3)/(x + 11)(x + 7)", "answer": "-23", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(x + 7)\n(x + 7) + 2(x + 11) \u003d 2(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 7) + 2(x + 11) - 2(x + 3) \u003d 0\n(x + 23) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-23\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(3x + 11) + 2/(x + 2) \u003d (x + 3)/(3x + 11)(x + 2)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 11)(x + 2)\n4(x + 2) + 2(3x + 11) \u003d (x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 2) + 2(3x + 11) - (x + 3) \u003d 0\n9(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 5) + 4/3(x + 1) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(x + 5)(x + 1)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 1)\n2(x + 1) + 4(x + 5)/3 \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 1) + 4(x + 5)/3 - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 8)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 10) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 2)/(x + 10)(x + 1)", "answer": "-11", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1) + (x + 10) \u003d (3x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1) + (x + 10) - (3x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 11) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-11\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 10) + 1/2(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 10)(x + 3)", "answer": "14", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 3)\n2(x + 3) + (x + 10)/2 \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 3) + (x + 10)/2 - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n(-x + 14)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n14\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(2x + 7) + 1/(x + 3) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(2x + 7)(x + 3)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 7)(x + 3)\n(x + 3) + (2x + 7) \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 3) + (2x + 7) - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n-x \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/3(x + 1) + 3/4(x + 2) \u003d (2x + 3)/(x + 1)(x + 2)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 2)\n4(x + 2)/3 + 3(x + 1)/4 \u003d (2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 2)/3 + 3(x + 1)/4 - (2x + 3) \u003d 0\n(x + 5)/12 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 5) + 2/(x + 5) \u003d (x + 10)/(2x + 5)(x + 5)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(x + 5)\n2(x + 5) + 2(2x + 5) \u003d (x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 5) + 2(2x + 5) - (x + 10) \u003d 0\n5(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(x + 8) + 2/(x + 1) \u003d (3x + 11)/(x + 8)(x + 1)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 8)(x + 1)\n4(x + 1) + 2(x + 8) \u003d (3x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 1) + 2(x + 8) - (3x + 11) \u003d 0\n3(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/4(x + 2) + 1/(x + 10) \u003d (2x + 3)/(x + 2)(x + 10)", "answer": "26", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 10)\n3(x + 10)/4 + (x + 2) \u003d (2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 10)/4 + (x + 2) - (2x + 3) \u003d 0\n(-x + 26)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n26\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 10) + 1/(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 2)/(3x + 10)(x + 2)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 10)(x + 2)\n2(x + 2) + (3x + 10) \u003d (3x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 2) + (3x + 10) - (3x + 2) \u003d 0\n2(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(x + 1) + 3/(x + 3) \u003d 3/(x + 1)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)\n3(x + 3)/2 + 3(x + 1) \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 3)/2 + 3(x + 1) - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\n3(x - 1)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(4x + 3) + 1/(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 7)/(4x + 3)(x + 2)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 3)(x + 2)\n2(x + 2) + (4x + 3) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 2) + (4x + 3) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n3(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(3x + 4) + 1/(2x + 9) \u003d (4x + 11)/(3x + 4)(2x + 9)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 4)(2x + 9)\n3(2x + 9) + (3x + 4) \u003d (4x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(2x + 9) + (3x + 4) - (4x + 11) \u003d 0\n5(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 4) + 1/(x + 2) \u003d (4x + 5)/(x + 4)(x + 2)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 2)\n2(x + 2) + (x + 4) \u003d (4x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 2) + (x + 4) - (4x + 5) \u003d 0\n(-x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 7) + 2/(4x + 7) \u003d (4x + 3)/(x + 7)(4x + 7)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 7)(4x + 7)\n(4x + 7) + 2(x + 7) \u003d (4x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(4x + 7) + 2(x + 7) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\n2(x + 9) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(4x + 7) + 2/(x + 7) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(4x + 7)(x + 7)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 7)(x + 7)\n2(x + 7) + 2(4x + 7) \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 7) + 2(4x + 7) - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n6(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/4(x + 2) + 3/(3x + 1) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 2)(3x + 1)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(3x + 1)\n(3x + 1)/4 + 3(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 1)/4 + 3(x + 2) - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n3(x + 3)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 5) + 3/(x + 7) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(x + 5)(x + 7)", "answer": "-16", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 7)\n(x + 7) + 3(x + 5) \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 7) + 3(x + 5) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 16) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-16\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 1/2(2x + 3) \u003d 3(x + 3)/(x + 1)(2x + 3)", "answer": "-11", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(2x + 3)\n(2x + 3) + (x + 1)/2 \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 3) + (x + 1)/2 - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\n(-x - 11)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-11\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 11) + 2/(x + 2) \u003d 1/(x + 2)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)\n2(x + 2) + 2(x + 11) \u003d (x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 2) + 2(x + 11) - (x + 11) \u003d 0\n3(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 6) + 1/(x + 4) \u003d (3x + 5)/(x + 6)(x + 4)", "answer": "5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 6)(x + 4)\n(x + 4) + (x + 6) \u003d (3x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 4) + (x + 6) - (3x + 5) \u003d 0\n(-x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 2) + 1/2(2x + 1) \u003d 4(x + 1)/(x + 2)(2x + 1)", "answer": "2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(2x + 1)\n2(2x + 1) + (x + 2)/2 \u003d 4(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(2x + 1) + (x + 2)/2 - 4(x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x - 2)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(4x + 11) + 1/(3x + 4) \u003d 2(2x + 3)/(4x + 11)(3x + 4)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 11)(3x + 4)\n(3x + 4) + (4x + 11) \u003d 2(2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 4) + (4x + 11) - 2(2x + 3) \u003d 0\n3(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/3(x + 3) + 1/(x + 5) \u003d (2x + 1)/(x + 3)(x + 5)", "answer": "-26", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 5)\n4(x + 5)/3 + (x + 3) \u003d (2x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 5)/3 + (x + 3) - (2x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x + 26)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-26\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 1) + 3/2(2x + 1) \u003d (3x + 11)/(x + 1)(2x + 1)", "answer": "-18", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(2x + 1)\n(2x + 1)/2 + 3(x + 1)/2 \u003d (3x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 1)/2 + 3(x + 1)/2 - (3x + 11) \u003d 0\n(-x - 18)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-18\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 5) + 1/(2x + 11) \u003d (3x + 1)/(x + 5)(2x + 11)", "answer": "-13", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(2x + 11)\n2(2x + 11) + (x + 5) \u003d (3x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(2x + 11) + (x + 5) - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\n2(x + 13) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-13\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 8) + 1/(x + 3) \u003d (4x + 3)/(3x + 8)(x + 3)", "answer": "-11", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 8)(x + 3)\n2(x + 3) + (3x + 8) \u003d (4x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 3) + (3x + 8) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\n(x + 11) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-11\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 3) + 4/(x + 5) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(x + 3)(x + 5)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 5)\n(x + 5) + 4(x + 3) \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 5) + 4(x + 3) - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 2/(x + 11) \u003d 2(x + 5)/(x + 2)(x + 11)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 11)\n(x + 11) + 2(x + 2) \u003d 2(x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 11) + 2(x + 2) - 2(x + 5) \u003d 0\n(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 2) + 1/3(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 2)(x + 3)", "answer": "-17", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 3)\n3(x + 3) + (x + 2)/3 \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 3) + (x + 2)/3 - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n(x + 17)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-17\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(x + 4) + 3/(x + 7) \u003d (4x + 9)/(x + 4)(x + 7)", "answer": "-27", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 7)\n3(x + 7)/2 + 3(x + 4) \u003d (4x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 7)/2 + 3(x + 4) - (4x + 9) \u003d 0\n(x + 27)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-27\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(3x + 5) + 3/2(x + 2) \u003d 2(x + 3)/(3x + 5)(x + 2)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 5)(x + 2)\n(x + 2) + 3(3x + 5)/2 \u003d 2(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 2) + 3(3x + 5)/2 - 2(x + 3) \u003d 0\n7(x + 1)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 2/(x + 4) \u003d 4(x + 1)/(x + 2)(x + 4)", "answer": "4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 4)\n(x + 4) + 2(x + 2) \u003d 4(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 4) + 2(x + 2) - 4(x + 1) \u003d 0\n(-x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 5) + 1/(3x + 10) \u003d (2x + 9)/(x + 5)(3x + 10)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(3x + 10)\n(3x + 10) + (x + 5) \u003d (2x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 10) + (x + 5) - (2x + 9) \u003d 0\n2(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 3) + 1/(x + 10) \u003d (x + 7)/(x + 3)(x + 10)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 10)\n(x + 10)/2 + (x + 3) \u003d (x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 10)/2 + (x + 3) - (x + 7) \u003d 0\n(x + 2)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(x + 3) + 3/2(x + 1) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(x + 3)(x + 1)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1)/2 + 3(x + 3)/2 \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1)/2 + 3(x + 3)/2 - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n(-x - 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(2x + 7) + 4/(2x + 11) \u003d (4x + 1)/(2x + 7)(2x + 11)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 7)(2x + 11)\n3(2x + 11) + 4(2x + 7) \u003d (4x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(2x + 11) + 4(2x + 7) - (4x + 1) \u003d 0\n10(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 5) + 3/(3x + 8) \u003d (3x + 7)/(3x + 5)(3x + 8)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 5)(3x + 8)\n2(3x + 8) + 3(3x + 5) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(3x + 8) + 3(3x + 5) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n12(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 3) + 2/(2x + 7) \u003d (2x + 3)/(x + 3)(2x + 7)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(2x + 7)\n(2x + 7) + 2(x + 3) \u003d (2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 7) + 2(x + 3) - (2x + 3) \u003d 0\n2(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/3(x + 2) + 1/(4x + 9) \u003d 2(x + 1)/(x + 2)(4x + 9)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(4x + 9)\n(4x + 9)/3 + (x + 2) \u003d 2(x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(4x + 9)/3 + (x + 2) - 2(x + 1) \u003d 0\n(x + 9)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(4x + 11) + 1/(x + 4) \u003d (2x + 11)/(4x + 11)(x + 4)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 11)(x + 4)\n2(x + 4) + (4x + 11) \u003d (2x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 4) + (4x + 11) - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\n4(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 3) + 2/(x + 4) \u003d (2x + 5)/(x + 3)(x + 4)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 4)\n(x + 4) + 2(x + 3) \u003d (2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 4) + 2(x + 3) - (2x + 5) \u003d 0\n(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 7) + 3/2(x + 4) \u003d (2x + 5)/(x + 7)(x + 4)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 7)(x + 4)\n2(x + 4) + 3(x + 7)/2 \u003d (2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 4) + 3(x + 7)/2 - (2x + 5) \u003d 0\n3(x + 9)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 10) + 2/(x + 9) \u003d (2x + 9)/(x + 10)(x + 9)", "answer": "-20", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 9)\n(x + 9) + 2(x + 10) \u003d (2x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 9) + 2(x + 10) - (2x + 9) \u003d 0\n(x + 20) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-20\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(2x + 1) + 1/(x + 4) \u003d (2x + 9)/(2x + 1)(x + 4)", "answer": "12", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(x + 4)\n(x + 4)/2 + (2x + 1) \u003d (2x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 4)/2 + (2x + 1) - (2x + 9) \u003d 0\n(x - 12)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n12\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 4) + 1/(2x + 5) \u003d 3(x + 3)/(x + 4)(2x + 5)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(2x + 5)\n(2x + 5) + (x + 4) \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 5) + (x + 4) - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\n0(0x0) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 6) + 1/(3x + 10) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 6)(3x + 10)", "answer": "-12", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 6)(3x + 10)\n(3x + 10) + (x + 6) \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 10) + (x + 6) - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n(x + 12) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-12\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 3/(2x + 3) \u003d (3x + 7)/(x + 2)(2x + 3)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(2x + 3)\n(2x + 3) + 3(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 3) + 3(x + 2) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n2(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/2(x + 5) + 1/(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 8)/(x + 5)(x + 2)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 2)\n3(x + 2)/2 + (x + 5) \u003d (3x + 8)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 2)/2 + (x + 5) - (3x + 8) \u003d 0\n(-x)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 7) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(3x + 7)(x + 1)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 7)(x + 1)\n2(x + 1) + (3x + 7) \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 1) + (3x + 7) - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n(x - 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 10) + 1/(x + 8) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(3x + 10)(x + 8)", "answer": "-10", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 10)(x + 8)\n2(x + 8) + (3x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 8) + (3x + 10) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n2(x + 10) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-10\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(4x + 5) + 1/(x + 7) \u003d (x + 8)/(4x + 5)(x + 7)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 5)(x + 7)\n3(x + 7) + (4x + 5) \u003d (x + 8)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 7) + (4x + 5) - (x + 8) \u003d 0\n6(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/4(x + 1) + 3/(3x + 8) \u003d (4x + 7)/(x + 1)(3x + 8)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(3x + 8)\n(3x + 8)/4 + 3(x + 1) \u003d (4x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 8)/4 + 3(x + 1) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\n(-x - 8)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/4(x + 1) + 1/2(x + 5) \u003d (x + 2)/(x + 1)(x + 5)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 5)\n3(x + 5)/4 + (x + 1)/2 \u003d (x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 5)/4 + (x + 1)/2 - (x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 9)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(3x + 10) + 1/(x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(3x + 10)(x + 10)", "answer": "-14", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 10)(x + 10)\n(x + 10) + (3x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 10) + (3x + 10) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 14) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-14\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 5) + 3/(x + 10) \u003d (4x + 9)/(x + 5)(x + 10)", "answer": "22", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 10)\n(x + 10)/2 + 3(x + 5) \u003d (4x + 9)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 10)/2 + 3(x + 5) - (4x + 9) \u003d 0\n(-x + 22)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n22\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 1/(x + 5) \u003d 2(2x + 1)/(x + 1)(x + 5)", "answer": "2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 5)\n(x + 5) + (x + 1) \u003d 2(2x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 5) + (x + 1) - 2(2x + 1) \u003d 0\n-2(x - 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(3x + 11) + 2/(x + 7) \u003d (3x + 7)/(3x + 11)(x + 7)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 11)(x + 7)\n3(x + 7) + 2(3x + 11) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 7) + 2(3x + 11) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n6(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 3) + 2/(x + 5) \u003d (3x + 7)/(2x + 3)(x + 5)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(x + 5)\n2(x + 5) + 2(2x + 3) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 5) + 2(2x + 3) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n3(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 1) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d (2x + 7)/(x + 1)(x + 1)", "answer": "4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 1)\n2(x + 1) + (x + 1) \u003d (2x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 1) + (x + 1) - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\n(x - 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 11) + 3/2(2x + 3) \u003d (3x + 10)/(x + 11)(2x + 3)", "answer": "-19", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(2x + 3)\n(2x + 3) + 3(x + 11)/2 \u003d (3x + 10)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 3) + 3(x + 11)/2 - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\n(x + 19)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-19\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(x + 5) + 2/(x + 9) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(x + 5)(x + 9)", "answer": "-18", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 9)\n4(x + 9) + 2(x + 5) \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 9) + 2(x + 5) - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n2(x + 18) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-18\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 4/(3x + 10) \u003d 2(x + 2)/(x + 1)(3x + 10)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(3x + 10)\n(3x + 10) + 4(x + 1) \u003d 2(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 10) + 4(x + 1) - 2(x + 2) \u003d 0\n5(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 3) + 2/(3x + 8) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(x + 3)(3x + 8)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(3x + 8)\n(3x + 8)/2 + 2(x + 3) \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 8)/2 + 2(x + 3) - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n(-x)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/3(x + 2) + 2/(4x + 1) \u003d (3x + 2)/(x + 2)(4x + 1)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(4x + 1)\n(4x + 1)/3 + 2(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(4x + 1)/3 + 2(x + 2) - (3x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 7)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(2x + 3) + 1/(x + 2) \u003d (2x + 11)/(2x + 3)(x + 2)", "answer": "6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(x + 2)\n(x + 2) + (2x + 3) \u003d (2x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 2) + (2x + 3) - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\n(x - 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(2x + 11) + 1/(x + 2) \u003d (4x + 1)/(2x + 11)(x + 2)", "answer": "12", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 11)(x + 2)\n(x + 2) + (2x + 11) \u003d (4x + 1)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 2) + (2x + 11) - (4x + 1) \u003d 0\n(-x + 12) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n12\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 3) + 1/3(x + 2) \u003d (2x + 11)/(x + 3)(x + 2)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 2)\n3(x + 2) + (x + 3)/3 \u003d (2x + 11)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 2) + (x + 3)/3 - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\n4(x - 3)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 1) + 3/(x + 2) \u003d (4x + 7)/(x + 1)(x + 2)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 2)\n2(x + 2) + 3(x + 1) \u003d (4x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 2) + 3(x + 1) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\nx \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/3(x + 3) + 2/(2x + 9) \u003d (3x + 4)/(x + 3)(2x + 9)", "answer": "15", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(2x + 9)\n(2x + 9)/3 + 2(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 9)/3 + 2(x + 3) - (3x + 4) \u003d 0\n(-x + 15)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n15\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/(2x + 1) + 4/(x + 3) \u003d 4(x + 2)/(2x + 1)(x + 3)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(x + 3)\n4(x + 3) + 4(2x + 1) \u003d 4(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 3) + 4(2x + 1) - 4(x + 2) \u003d 0\n8(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 5) + 3/2(x + 4) \u003d 3(x + 3)/(x + 5)(x + 4)", "answer": "5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 4)\n(x + 4) + 3(x + 5)/2 \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 4) + 3(x + 5)/2 - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\n(-x + 5)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 3/(2x + 11) \u003d 4/(2x + 11)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 11)\n(2x + 11) + 3(x + 2) \u003d 4(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 11) + 3(x + 2) - 4(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 9) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n4/3(x + 1) + 2/(x + 3) \u003d 3/(x + 1)", "answer": "9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)\n4(x + 3)/3 + 2(x + 1) \u003d 3(x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n4(x + 3)/3 + 2(x + 1) - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\n(x - 9)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(2x + 1) + 3/2(2x + 3) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(2x + 1)(2x + 3)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(2x + 3)\n(2x + 3)/2 + 3(2x + 1)/2 \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(2x + 3)/2 + 3(2x + 1)/2 - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x - 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 5) + 1/4(x + 2) \u003d (x + 4)/(x + 5)(x + 2)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 2)\n(x + 2) + (x + 5)/4 \u003d (x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 2) + (x + 5)/4 - (x + 4) \u003d 0\n(x - 3)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 1) + 4/(3x + 1) \u003d 2(x + 4)/(x + 1)(3x + 1)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(3x + 1)\n(3x + 1)/2 + 4(x + 1) \u003d 2(x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 1)/2 + 4(x + 1) - 2(x + 4) \u003d 0\n7(x - 1)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 10) + 2/(x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 2)/(x + 10)(x + 10)", "answer": "-34", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 10)\n2(x + 10) + 2(x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 10) + 2(x + 10) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 34) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-34\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 3) + 1/(x + 3) \u003d (x + 4)/(x + 3)(x + 3)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 3)\n(x + 3) + (x + 3) \u003d (x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 3) + (x + 3) - (x + 4) \u003d 0\n(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(x + 6) + 4/(x + 7) \u003d 2(2x + 5)/(x + 6)(x + 7)", "answer": "-14", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 6)(x + 7)\n2(x + 7) + 4(x + 6) \u003d 2(2x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 7) + 4(x + 6) - 2(2x + 5) \u003d 0\n2(x + 14) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-14\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(2x + 5) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d (x + 8)/(2x + 5)(x + 1)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1) + (2x + 5) \u003d (x + 8)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1) + (2x + 5) - (x + 8) \u003d 0\n4(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/4(x + 2) + 2/(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 2)/(x + 2)(x + 2)", "answer": "14", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 2)\n3(x + 2)/4 + 2(x + 2) \u003d (3x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 2)/4 + 2(x + 2) - (3x + 2) \u003d 0\n(-x + 14)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n14\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 2) + 1/(3x + 5) \u003d (3x + 7)/(x + 2)(3x + 5)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(3x + 5)\n(3x + 5) + (x + 2) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 5) + (x + 2) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\nx \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n3/(x + 4) + 1/(x + 1) \u003d (2x + 3)/(x + 4)(x + 1)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 1)\n3(x + 1) + (x + 4) \u003d (2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n3(x + 1) + (x + 4) - (2x + 3) \u003d 0\n2(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/3(x + 3) + 2/(x + 4) \u003d (3x + 7)/(x + 3)(x + 4)", "answer": "5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 4)\n2(x + 4)/3 + 2(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 4)/3 + 2(x + 3) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\n(-x + 5)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(2x + 5) + 4/(4x + 11) \u003d 2(2x + 3)/(2x + 5)(4x + 11)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(4x + 11)\n2(4x + 11) + 4(2x + 5) \u003d 2(2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(4x + 11) + 4(2x + 5) - 2(2x + 3) \u003d 0\n12(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/2(x + 3) + 1/(x + 3) \u003d (2x + 3)/(x + 3)(x + 3)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 3)\n(x + 3)/2 + (x + 3) \u003d (2x + 3)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 3)/2 + (x + 3) - (2x + 3) \u003d 0\n(-x + 3)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 1) + 4/(x + 10) \u003d (4x + 5)/(x + 1)(x + 10)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 10)\n(x + 10) + 4(x + 1) \u003d (4x + 5)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 10) + 4(x + 1) - (4x + 5) \u003d 0\n(x + 9) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 3) + 1/2(x + 4) \u003d (x + 2)/(x + 3)(x + 4)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 4)\n(x + 4) + (x + 3)/2 \u003d (x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(x + 4) + (x + 3)/2 - (x + 2) \u003d 0\n(x + 7)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n1/(x + 10) + 3/(3x + 4) \u003d (x + 4)/(x + 10)(3x + 4)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(3x + 4)\n(3x + 4) + 3(x + 10) \u003d (x + 4)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n(3x + 4) + 3(x + 10) - (x + 4) \u003d 0\n5(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/3(x + 3) + 1/(x + 7) \u003d 2(x + 2)/(x + 3)(x + 7)", "answer": "11", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 7)\n2(x + 7)/3 + (x + 3) \u003d 2(x + 2)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 7)/3 + (x + 3) - 2(x + 2) \u003d 0\n(-x + 11)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n11\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "text", "question": "Solve for x:\n2/(3x + 11) + 1/(x + 9) \u003d (4x + 7)/(3x + 11)(x + 9)", "answer": "-22", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 11)(x + 9)\n2(x + 9) + (3x + 11) \u003d (4x + 7)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n2(x + 9) + (3x + 11) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\n(x + 22) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-22\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"}
]}